OCHOLLAH KENNEDY ONGENG PRI SCHOOL P.O .Box 24-4032.RODI-KOPANY

Online CV: https://ochollah.github.io CONTACT: 0711176811

April 19

The Human Resources' Manager ORGANIZATION/COMPANY P.O Box 0001, Nairobi

Dear Sir/ Madam,

REF: APPLICATION FOR ADVERTISED/VACANT POSITION:.

I am writing in relation to the above mentioned position. As advertised, I possess experience in software development in PHP, Java, JavaScript/ data analysis, systems management and web development, html5 ,CSS, and LAN, WAN networking in computing after pursuing Bsc. computer science, software option.

Currently though am the IT PROJECT LEAD at MOREC-ICT based resource Foundation in Homa-Bay County where am tasked with improving information communication and technology needs of residents of rural Kenya counties and enable them be productive contributors to the economic growth thus building modern society. SAMPLES: https://kenoxfirm.github.io https://ke

Recently, I was in charge of the IT department as the information systems officer with Children Of God Relief Institute (COGRI) leatoto program where tasked with management of the data from all the 9 data centers collected by data clerks both in the field and at the centers and LAN networking . Additionally, I have served as the IT support technician with CITAM foundation where I was in charge of the IT Department, repairing broken computers, installations of new software's, updating, backup of data, troubleshooting and configuring of LAN network.

Over and above, my approach to work goes beyond my job description, as I am always looking for ways to improve efficiency and reduce costs. I am well versed in leading teams. I am looking forward to playing a vital role in IT management and solutions and adding significant value to your company. Thank you for your time and consideration.

sincerely,

ooh

Ochollah Kennedy





KENNEDY OCHOLLAH ICT SUPPORT OFFICER

SUMMARY

Competent and seasoned ICT support officer,

technician with four years' experience in variety of office based environments

Demonstrated success in administering ICT

procedures in a practical and user friendly manner, ensuring many IT problems able to be solved via the telephone

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

 Operating Systems like Mac, Windows (all

EXPERIENCE

LEAD COMMUNITY ICT SPECIALIST • MORIAH RESOURCE CENTER • MARCH 2018- DECEMBER 2018

- Responsible for diagnosing & resolving hardware, software & end users problems.
- Acting as the first point of contact for all IT & technical queries.
- Developing the infrastructure and systems to meet the organization's needs.
- Configuring and managing backup & restore procedures.
- Maintaining a wide range of computer hardware and software programmes.
- Provide secondary support for LAN/WAN configuration networking.
- Developing online marketing skills that will see youths and job seekers learn digital skills that will boost their employability, build web designs and user experience.
- Enhance technical skill for job creation and employability of the population served
- Manage the business center that provided all computer related and internet services to the locals.

DATA CLERK • HOLY FAMILY ORIANG HEALTH CENTER • JANUARY-FEBRUARY 2018

- Data entry into the system
- Systems update and maintenance



KOK

KENNEDY OCHOLLA

ICT SUPPORT OFFICER

- versions), UNIX, and Macintosh.
- Windows Server package
- Setting up LAN network and repairing as well as maintaining it.
- Software installation and maintenance skills
- Servers: WAMP, XAMMP, Tomcat/ Apache, windows servers.
- Software:
 CS5.Netbeans
 JDK, WordPress,
 MS. Office 365,
- Languages: JAVA, JAVASCRIPT, PHP, C, C++, HTML, XML, CSS, ASP.NET.
- Database: MS ACCESS, MySQL, SQL

- Training staff on Systems implementation
- Registration of new patients
- NHIF registration both outpatient and inpatient, Linda mama registration.

INFORMATION S\$YSTEM OFFICER (ISO) • CHILDREN OF GOD RELIEF INSTITUTE (COGRI)_NYUMBANI CHILDRENS' HOME(LEATOTO PROGRAME) • MARCH- DECEMBER 2017

- Provide day to day end user support on general computer applications and IT systems in the Office and centers.
- Technical Support. Installed and performed minor repairs to hardware, software, and peripheral equipment, following design or installation specifications.
- IT Asset Management- Maintained an asset register for all IT equipment including hardware, software, telecommunication and network equipment.

IT SUPPORT TECHNICIAN • CHRIST IS THE ANSWER MINISTRIES (CITAM) • FEBRUARY 2014- NOVEMBER 2014

- Networking LAN wireless internet trouble-shootings.
- Maintenance of Data integrity including, Antivirus software management, Backups and Restore Maintain high level of data protection
- Database management and designing, Systems planning and designing,
- Management of telephone systems, office equipment including faxes, copiers, scanners
- Network cabling and management of active devices

EDUCATION

Maasai Mara University — Kenya

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Second Class Upper Division







KENNEDY OCHOLLA

ICT SUPPORT OFFICER

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Excellent oral, written and presentation communication skills.
- Problem-solving orientation and resourcefulness
- Troubleshooting
- Comfortable working as part of a team or independently

HTML certification 2009-2013

Obera Mixed Secondary School- Kenya

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education, B+, 2004-2007

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- HTML and CSS Certification, Template monster Year 2018
- Certificate in Project Management, Brentwood University e-learning College. Year 2018
- Online Training Yalinetworks 2015: Young African Leaders Initiative Program (Yalinetwork) Usa (2015)

REFRENCES

Cosmas Ochieng' John Makau **Marshel Ochieng** Data Manager, Holy Family Founding Director, MOREC Project Manager, COGRI NYUMBANI Oriang Health Center P.O. Box 45774-00100, Nairobi. P.O. Box Nairobi. P.O. Box. Cell: 0725398675 Cell: 0722201163 Cell: 0716098798 Email:cosmas@moreckenya.org Email: makau@nyumbani.org Email: marshelochieng@yahoo.com

